#### SAMUEL TAN ZHI WEI

samueltan.9803@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/tanzhiweisamuel · 83820207

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Dedicated Computer Science Student with a passion for all thing tech related. Experience with Data Analytics, Software Engineering and Machine Learning. Confident in my ability to quickly pick up anything I'm passionate about, committed to continuous self-improvement and impacting team success. Portfolio: https://react-portfolio-zeta-rouge.vercel.app

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

#### PSA Data Analytics Intern

May 2022 - Dec 2022

- Used **Pandas | Python** to analyze shipping routes and other shipping related information. **Streamlit** to Dashboard shipping information.
- Created a script funnel for generating vessel port of rotation as well as port to port coordinates, utilizing machine learning techniques to identify complex patterns.

NIUM Product Intern May 2021 – Aug 2021

- NoSQL | MongoDB to support Product team.
- Enhanced user experience by identifying AML (anti-fraud) hits were inefficient | Collaborated with Product Analytics teams to develop and implement **MongoDB Chart** to visualize inefficiencies in real time.

# 1st Commando Battalion - Singapore Armed Forces | 3SG (Third Sergeant)

Jul 2018 - May 2020

• Managed team of men, overseeing discipline, training, and professional growth.

#### **PROJECTS**

GODOT | GDScript Current

- Art, Music, and Logic
- https://phatwhale.itch.io/

### NFT Marketplace App + Showcase Webapp | React + React Native | JS

2022

- React Webapp, Simple proof of concept for JS, HTML, CSS
- React Native NFT Marketplace, UI for an NFT Marketplace app (Static Data)
- https://nft-showcase-react.vercel.app

### Carpark App | Android Studio | Java

2021

- Determine nearest carpark using Google maps API & Determine Carpark Availability
- Using data.gov API to get public carpark information

### Telegram Bot for NTU Saraca Hall | python-telegram-bot | python

2020

- Used to communicate with residents with FAQ and event signups
- During the pandemic we sold ART test kits, since there was a need for "on-demand" purchases
- Notify the team when a new purchase order is made

# **EDUCATION**

# Nanyang Technological University

Aug 2020 - Current

# Degree in Computer Science | GPA 4.22

- Basketball Hall 2020-2023, Swimming IVP 2020-2023, Swimming Captain 2021-2022
- Saraca Hall Vice-President 2021-2022, Saraca Hall Welfare Director 2020-2021

# **Singapore Polytechnic**

Apr 2015 - Mar 2018

### Diploma in Aerospace Electronics | GPA 3.84

- Gold with Honors CCA, Certificate in Aviation Management, Japanese Language 1&2 Distinction
- LEAP Camp Foundation & Intermediate (Leadership camps), Water polo Captain 2016-2017

### **LANGUAGE AND TECHNOLOGIES**

- C++, C, Java, Python, SQL, JavaScript, Typescript, CSS, HTML
- React, React Native, Pandas, Django, PowerBI